<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="8" created="2025-05-30" category="standard" status="draft" title="Software Multimodal User Interface (MUI) Framework">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="12"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<embed src="./overview.svg"/>
				<p>
					Generally speaking, a software or computer may contain User Interfaces (UIs),
					as Graphical User Interface (GUI), Acoustic User Interface (AUI), Haptic User Interface (HUI)
					and Kinesthetic User Interface (KUI). All of them require Human Interface Devices (HIDs)
					as the media of interactions between the user and the software.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Multimodal User Interface (MUI) Framework Basis">
			<content>
				<p>
					Each UI plays a role in the MUI Framework by their responsibilities.
					Altogether provides the complete UI framework where users may interact with.
					Different UI may interoperate differently with different counterparts to integrate
					the roles to achieve various features users use.
				</p>
			</content>
			<section title="Graphical User Interface (GUI)">
				<content>
					<p>
						The GUI is the most basic part of a UI to display information to users.
					</p>
					<p>
						The rendering information of GUI is transferred to displays for conversions
						from electronic signals to electromagnetic energy using electrons.
						Light information is then transmitted to users' eyes for visual experience.
					</p>
					<p>
						Visual information is mostly based on screen coordinates and colors,
						so the distinguishment of different GUI elements is by the differences in colors
						and the relative positions of contents.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Acoustic User Interface (AUI)">
				<content>
					<p>
						When there is the GUI, AUI enhances User Experience (UX) by providing another
						sense of experience to users.
					</p>
					<p>
						The acoustic information of AUI is transferred to speakers for conversions
						from electronic signals to kinetic energy of particles by vibrations.
						Sound information is then transmitted to users' ears for aural experience.
					</p>
					<p>
						Auditory information is mostly based on frequencies and amplitudes of sound waves,
						so different AUI contents are by the qualities of sound waves combined from
						different audio sources.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Haptic User Interface (HUI)">
				<content>
					<p>
						Occasionally, HUI exists to enhance the immersion of UX to users.
					</p>
					<p>
						The haptic information from HUI is transferred from electronic signals
						to kinetic energy of mechanical parts of tactile HIDs.
						Users sense the movement of bodies made by the kinetic energy.
					</p>
					<p>
						Most likely, HUI is geared by motors, for example in mobile phones and
						game controllers. The initiation would mostly be associated with
						specific scenarios from other events or user interactions.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Kinesthetic User Interface (KUI)">
				<content>
					<p>
						Essentially, KUI motivates the feedbacks from users to the software or computer.
					</p>
					<p>
						Users may initiate any interactions to the computer via inputs to HIDs.
						Analog information detected by the HIDs is then transmitted to the computer
						for analysis of interactions as electronic signals to the software or computer.
					</p>
					<p>
						Most commonly, related HIDs include but not limited to keyboards,
						pointing devices, motion sensors, trackers and controllers.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="Interoperation of UIs">
			<content>
				<p>
					Most of the time, different UIs work together to complete the entire UX to users.
				</p>
				<p>
					Especially for GUI frameworks, KUI typically plays the critical role to feed
					user interactions back to GUI for further processing. GUI may also sometimes
					communicate with AUI to play audio indicated by user interactions.
					In some cases, GUI and AUI may be associated, especially when playing videos
					with audio channels.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
