<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="11" created="2026-03-21" category="process" status="draft" title="Orryx Alpha Stage">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="21"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					Alpha and Beta Stages of Orryx would be proposed separately. Until the end of the Stage,
					its proposal would be held <b>Provisional</b>.
				</p>
				<p>
					In Alpha Stage, versions are under the theme of "Basis of Basics", with the major version zero.
					During this Stage, no storage systems and customizations would be implemented, but rather
					demonstrations of basic mechanisms of Orryx. This is unlike demo testing.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Version Schedules">
			<content>
				<p>
					All versions are incremented only on the minor version in the Primary Version, starting from
					version 0.0.1.
				</p>
			</content>
			<section title="v0.0.1: Physics">
				<content>
					<p>
						Demonstration may be basically based on physics implementation of Simple Terra with certain
						extra features to interact with the World. At least, some functionalities should have been
						available in this version.
					</p>
					<p>
						Random bodies may be generated to test for collisions and various features. Those bodies may
						resemble certain kinds of Tiles and Entities. Players may control a sphere around the World.
						For bodies, it may be possible to test for mechanisms for continuous Tiles in physics.
						Tiles may be kinematic to be static for other moving bodies.
					</p>
					<p>
						On start, there would be no menus, but directly in a physics World after a startup animation.
						The content of the animation is yet purely demonstrative and not ready for production.
					</p>
				</content>
				<section title="Structures">
					<content>
						<p>
							Different classes should hold different responsibilities precisely.
							<code>TerraModulus</code> hold a major <code>GuiManager</code> and another manager that
							is unrelated to User Interface (UI) as <code>World</code>.
							Since the implementation of World is demonstrative and temporary, related classes shall be
							placed under <code>net.terramodulus.void</code> package.
						</p>
						<p>
							<code>GuiManager</code> shall hold <code>Window</code>, <code>RenderSystem</code>,
							<code>ScreenManager</code>, and temporarily <code>InputSystem</code>.
							In each frame, all pending Multimodel UI (MUI) events shall be polled and analyzed,
							including storing all key events and processing them through <code>InputSystem</code>.
							Then, <code>ScreenManager</code> shall update and refresh events to prepare for rendering.
							Eventually, Window's Canvas shall be cleared and rendered with contents of
							<code>Screen</code>(s) before swapping framebuffers.
						</p>
						<p>
							In <code>World</code>, there shall be an isolated <code>Thread</code> ticking Ferricia's
							<code>World</code> at a constant rate of 20 Hz. Ideally, time deltas should be calculated
							for more accurate ticking, ensuring expected ticks being processed for a duration.
							<code>PhyEnv</code> and <code>PhyWorld</code> must be created accordingly, with objects
							generated afterward. Objects shall be stored in a map with <code>ObjId</code> using randomly
							generated unique unsigned integers, with objects other than random test cubes created in
							a fixed way for main character and spawn point cube. In the creation of <code>World</code>,
							an instance of <code>Ymir</code> as the representative of preceding management in Client
							with association to rendering and its properties. Ideally, generations of objects shall be
							in parallel such that progress may be tracked on Graphical UI (GUI), without any invocation
							to OpenGL during generation but after the end of generation when the role of generation
							handed back to the main thread.
						</p>
						<p>
							<code>GameplayScreen</code> handles initialization of <code>World</code> and rendering of it.
							This includes the construction of <code>Ymir</code> and related <code>VoidGeom</code> classes.
							In the Screen, a helper dummy Component <code>GameplayRenderer</code> is used to render
							World objects after sorting, via <code>renderGwrGeo</code> from Ferricia.
							A representative of player character as <code>PlayerVoidGeom</code> shall also be stored
							in the <code>GameplayScreen</code>, though, it should not be a responsibility of a Screen.
							At the same time, objects stored in <code>World</code> must also provide ability to access
							information for rendering information without having to implement actual rendering-related
							functions and interfaces directly in <code>World</code>, isolating rendering responsibility.
							Events related to World should be handled in <code>update</code> functions, while others
							related to UI should be handled via event listeners; controlling of player-directed events
							shall also be handled via <code>GameplayScreen</code>.
						</p>
						<p>
							<code>ScreenManager</code> initially adds <code>LaunchingScreen</code>, showing an animation
							of logo of the host organization. Then, it transits to <code>ResourceLoadingScreen</code>,
							showing the logo of TerraModulus; it is intended to track progress of resource loading, but
							at the moment, there is no resource to load, a period of a second to stay on the logo without
							showing a progress bar may be realized instead. Eventually, normally it should transit to
							<code>TitleScreen</code>, but at this stage, <code>GameplayScreen</code> generated by
							<code>RenderSystem</code> instead; though, it is not ideal to pass <code>RenderSystem</code>
							through <code>update</code> functions.
						</p>
					</content>
				</section>
				<section title="Physics">
					<content>
						<p>
							Various functionalities would be reserved for later implementations of other features.
							However, for basic functions, basic body, mass and collision information should be done.
							Later in the future if possible, it is possible to also test Bullet's Engine, as a comparison.
						</p>
						<p>
							The physics of World shall be initiated starting from <code>PhyEnv</code> along with other
							top-level managers like <code>PhyWorld</code> and their internal management, upon creation.
							All Geom instances along with just a single <code>OdeGeom</code> without a Body shall be added
							to the same lower-level Hash Space; another Geom if Sphere with a Body shall be Player-controlled,
							stored directly in the Top-Level Space. There shall also be a Plane at y=-100 as a floor boundary,
							without other World boundaries.
						</p>
						<p>
							The <code>PhyWorld</code> holding all physics objects belonging to it is created by<code>PhyEnv</code>.
							Most likely all physics objects should have respective owned handles, and the <code>PhyWorld</code>
							and its underlying structures should only hold references to them. <code>PhyObj</code> has
							two implementations, <code>PhyBody</code> and <code>PhyGeom</code>, where <code>PhyBody</code>
							is the physics representation of a Body or Geom, and <code>PhyGeom</code> is the physics
							representation of a non-placeable Geom. <code>PhyRawGeom</code> fully holds a Geom initially
							upon creation but translation to <code>PhyGeom</code> destroys it.
						</p>
						<p>
							In the structures with ODE, <code>PhyEnv</code> shall hold <code>OdeHandle</code> handling library
							utilities and <code>CollisionManager</code> for collision handling assistance.
							<code>PhyWorld</code> shall hold <code>OdeWorld</code>, <code>TopLevelSpace</code> and a list of
							<code>PhyObj</code>. <code>TopLevelSpace</code> is the top-most Space, holding <code>OdeSpace</code>.
							<code>OdeWorld</code> is used to handle <code>OdeBody</code> while <code>OdeSpace</code> is used
							to handle <code>OdeGeom</code>. <code>PhyBody</code> holds either or both an <code>OdeBody</code>,
							or one or more references of <code>OdePlaceableGeom</code>. Associations of ODE Geom and ODE Body
							are handled by the abstraction of them in <code>PhyBody</code>. ODE Bodies are always created in
							<code>OdeWorld</code> while ODE Geoms are always created in <code>TopLevelSpace</code>.
						</p>
						<p>
							User-defined data should not be stored in ODE objects, but only on our side with those handling
							the interactions with those ODE objects. Mostly, <code>phy::ode</code> module handles abstraction
							of actions provided by ODE's interface, while other higher level operations should reside in
							<code>phy</code> module directly. Seemingly, Kryon's internal would directly interact with
							objects in <code>phy</code>, and indirectly with objects in <code>phy::ode</code>.
						</p>
						<p>
							For flexibility to support other physics libraries, the abstraction layer in <code>phy</code>
							module should be generalized enough with certain supporting functions in the future development
							for the flexibility for other physics backends, most likely using traits as abstraction, with
							the actual implementations initiated during initialization. This includes that library-dependent
							interfaces should not be exposed across the Java-Native Interface.
						</p>
						<p>
							Some Objects in the World would not be associated with any Body to be static. If some Objects
							need to move but without inference from other Objects, they still need to be kinematic Bodies.
							In a later stage, some Objects may be associated with a same Body as a Composite Body to test
							for Body dynamics of Bodies composite of multiple Geom instances.
						</p>
						<p>
							<code>PhyEnv</code> shall also handle collision activities observed by executing ODE's loop.
							<code>PhyCollisionManager</code> from <code>PhyEnv</code> handles collisions via underlying
							<code>OdeContactManager</code> by generating <code>OdeJoint</code> from <code>OdeContactParams</code>
							in <code>near_callback</code>, while all parameters depend on properties of objects in interaction.
							Those properties should be later defined by properties of Tiles and Entities, so they should
							be fully up and subject to Kryon.
						</p>
						<p>
							At this stage, very basic optimization on the collision algorithm shall be done. This includes
							benchmarked methods of using collision bits, intra-Space collision detection ignore list,
							and a finer Hash Space for the Space of cubes.
						</p>
					</content>
				</section>
				<section title="World">
					<content>
						<p>
							In World, there shall be a sphere as the player-controlled character, a spawn point cube
							and randomly generated cubes. While the sphere and the spawn point cube are always generated
							at fixed positions, as (0, 1, 0) and (0, 0, 0) respectively; the sphere should be just placed
							on the spawn point cube. Random cubes as test objects are generated using a fixed algorithm
							with sets of random continuous patterns for each five meters apart; those cubes are generated
							like maze generation that are branched from the origin and other branches.
						</p>
						<p>
							Currently, only geometries of unit sizes, lengths of one, are being generated. However,
							at later stage, more geometries shall be tested for support of more complex models that
							may appear in certain Tiles and Entities in reality. Also, those objects shall never rotate
							upon external forces as torques are mostly not valid in the principles of mechanisms in TerraModulus.
						</p>
						<p>
							Cubes shall be generated randomly in three colors, plain red, plain green and plain blue,
							while the sphere shall be in full white. Since the colors are plain, the differentiation
							to identify relative location would likely be difficult without shadows or other mechanisms
							that may help distinguishing distances of objects.
						</p>
						<p>
							In order to support feedbacks of collisions, the strategy to set velocities upon movement
							may not be compatible, as those impacts seemed to be handled by instantaneous forces, which
							result in calculated velocities. This means movements and other activities shall also act
							forces on it to make effects in motions of the objects to avoid conflicts and malfunctions.
							Therefore, movement shall be done by the unit direction vector resulted from player-directed
							movement direction commands via keys of movement commanding, which shall be <kbd>W</kbd>,
							<kbd>S</kbd>, <kbd>A</kbd>, <kbd>D</kbd>, <kbd>Shift</kbd> and <kbd>Space</kbd>. The movement
							commands should direct the intended direction for forces to be exerted on.
						</p>
						<p>
							The recommended amounts of forces and limits to be applied on should be well tested, so they
							may not be fixed even in the coming versions for balancing testing purposes. With plain
							guessing of effects without actual calculations, those numbers currently are:
						</p>
						<list>
							<li>The sphere has a mass of exactly 1.0, but in real implementation this may be larger.</li>
							<li>Maximal speed exerted by movement is π*π.</li>
							<li>Maximal acceleration exerted instantaneously is π*π.</li>
							<li>Minimal non-zero acceleration exerted instantaneously is 0.1, as epsilon.</li>
							<li>Default gravity is y=-9.81.</li>
							<li>Maximal gravity condition before multiplication is 20, meaning possibly 39.24.</li>
							<li>Maximal gravity condition before multiplication is 20, meaning possibly 39.24.</li>
							<li>Minimal gravity condition before division is 1, meaning possibly 0.613125.</li>
							<li>Possible frictions include zero, finite and infinity.</li>
							<li>Minimal finite frictions is 1/16.</li>
							<li>Maximal finite frictions is 64.</li>
						</list>
						<p>
							The movement calculation shall be done when the direction is not zero. Acceleration may not
							be applied at a tick when maximal velocity (as speed) has been attained with that direction.
							This is done by scalar projection of the instantaneous velocity on the target direction.
							If the scalar projection is less than the maximal speed, an acceleration shall be applied.
							Subtraction of the projection from the maximal speed is the maximal velocity to attain,
							but it has to be clamped by the epsilon and the maximal acceleration. The final force exerted
							shall be multiplication of the acceleration product of delta velocity and direction, and
							a mass of 1.0.
						</p>
					</content>
				</section>
				<section title="Rendering">
					<content>
						<p>
							Basically, since menus are incomplete at the current stage, temporary solutions for rendering
							shall be employed just for basic startup animations and Gameplay World Rendering (GWR).
							World rendering shall be handled by <code>GameplayScreen</code> via functions of GWR.
						</p>
						<p>
							During rendering, Geom objects shall be sorted first by y ascendingly, then z ascendingly.
							At the moment, depth buffer is not yet used to render better z-ordering for occlusion.
							There are currently only simple shapes and geometries being rendered, yet no more complex
							rendering at this stage, but more different rendering properties shall be tested later.
						</p>
						<p>
							All Geom objects must be in unit size of one meter in range of [-1,1] for local space.
							However, for unit objects with only a single shape, its dimensions must align the limits.
							This means the diameters or widths of the shapes should be two meters. As unit objects,
							rotation and scaling may be identity, but must be scaled half in model transformation.
						</p>
						<p>
							Graphical Menu Presentation (GMP) rendering is placed under <code>mui::rendering</code>
							while Gameplay Field Visualization (GFV) rendering is placed under <code>mui::rendering3d</code>,
							but ideally, certain functionalities and mechanisms should have been generalized out of them.
							GMP may involve both two-dimensional (2D) and three-dimensional (3D) rendering but GFV only
							involves 3D rendering in a different style from GMP rendering, so it may be complex handling.
							In general, GMP may composite simpler geometries and general graph rendering; GFV may involve
							composited meshes and combinations of different geometries as a whole.
							"Field" of GFV indicates the <i>Field of Camera View</i> (FVC) while GMP may be described as
							<i>Plane Interface</i>; Gameplay Scene Depiction (GSD) is the underlying environment of GFV.
						</p>
						<p>
							There are special treatments for View and Projection matrices in GFV. For the View,
							it is done by having a direction downward with an inclination of 30 degrees towards negative
							z-axis. For the Projection, the dimensions are constrained directly by canvas dimensions while
							there is no z-culling from viewpoint, along with magnification scaling and offset centering.
							Perspective transformation is invalid as per the Principles, but culling should be applied
							for most of the time to represent the Field in perspective of Player Character; this shall
							be implemented and tested at later stage.
						</p>
						<p>
							For Camera and sizing in GFV, standard magnification scaling shall be defined by 64 screen pixels
							per meter in World space, while normally it is expected that each Tile is rendered as 32-pixel
							width textures. This means each texture pixel should be rendered as two times two screen pixels.
						</p>
						<p>
							There is simple basic light rendering to help differentiate the faces of geometries being
							rendered in GFV, by a single directional light towards between negative y-axis and positive
							z-axis, in addition to 10% ambient effect. Currently, they are all white light. However,
							advanced light rendering like perspective occlusion and shadows shall be implemented later.
						</p>
						<p>
							Among 3D Geom structures in <code>mui::rendering3d</code>, only the Mesh variant is used.
							In order to simplify the codebase and amount of work, utilizing an existing geometry library
							that provides sufficient but not excessive functionalities shall be preferred in production.
							At later stage, refactoring the codebase to utilize more existing libraries to avoid reinventing
							the wheels shall be conducted under proper examination of libraries without violations to
							the intended features and functionalities, but with feasible flexibilities and adaptions.
						</p>
					</content>
				</section>
				<section title="Functions">
					<content>
						<p>
							Basically, users can control the sphere using the aforementioned hotkeys, along with other
							debugging hotkeys. Those keys can query states of the World and the sphere, and modify
							attributes of those, including World gravity, gravity influence, friction attributes given
							the capabilities of the physics engine.
						</p>
						<p>
							In details, movement keys add direction vectors when held; other hotkeys and functions include:
						</p>
						<list>
							<li><kbd>Q</kbd>: Query position of sphere.</li>
							<li><kbd>R</kbd>: Query velocity of sphere.</li>
							<li><kbd>U</kbd>: Query gravity of world and gravity mode of (influence to) sphere.</li>
							<li><kbd>I</kbd>: Toggle gravity mode of (influence to) sphere.</li>
							<li><kbd>O</kbd>: Increase world gravity.</li>
							<li><kbd>P</kbd>: Decrease world gravity.</li>
							<li><kbd>J</kbd>: Query friction states.</li>
							<li><kbd>K</kbd>: Toggle friction mode.</li>
							<li><kbd>L</kbd>: Increase friction (for Limited mode).</li>
							<li><kbd>M</kbd>: Decrease friction (for Limited mode).</li>
							<li><kbd>N</kbd>: Reset velocity of sphere to zero.</li>
							<li><kbd>=</kbd>: Zoom in camera.</li>
							<li><kbd>-</kbd>: Zoom out camera.</li>
						</list>
						<p>
							The units of vectors are directly come from the underlying physics engine. It is worth noting
							that resulted acceleration or force is hidden and difficult to be queried, so it is ignored.
							This includes the situation when multiple force sources exist to exert on, resulting a complex
							state to be queried directly, so effective frictions can be hard to be examined easily.
							The sphere can be either be influenced or not influenced by World gravity, according to
							the effective mode; there are value boundaries for gravity to be tweaked, and there is
							currently the parameter of downward (negative y-axis) gravity. There are three modes for
							friction: Zero, Limited and Infinite; where Limited friction means a finite value of
							the friction parameter shall be exerted, with a limited range of values. There was an
							attempt to reset coordinates of the sphere to the spawn point, but the consistency of
							physical states is difficult to be resolved, and thus currently only the velocity can be reset.
							Zoom level of camera ranged from 1/4 to 4, with 1 the default scaling factor.
						</p>
					</content>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section title="v0.0.2: Graphics">
				<content>
					<p></p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="v0.0.3: Mechanics">
				<content>
					<p></p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="v0.0.4: Genetics">
				<content>
					<p></p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="See also">
			<content>
				<list>
					<li>
						<a href=""></a>
					</li>
				</list>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
