<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="" created="2026-02-11" category="informational" status="draft"
     title="String Parsing and Resource Keys Considerations">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="14"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					Strings are useful and extensive in several circumstances, but sometimes it may introduce
					unnecessary burdens and overheads in different aspects. Conditions must have to be met
					before adapting string resources in codebase.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Location of Resources">
			<content>
				<p>
					If the resources are planned to be located within code, as hardcoded resources,
					it typically serves no advantages but disadvantages.
				</p>
				<p>
					Programmatically created resources should be more intuitive and faster than
					parsing string for deserialization.
				</p>
				<p>
					If the formation of resources is not trivial, object builders could be utilized for
					advanced construction of objects. Unless the structure of resources are highly bound
					to the formation of literals, like Regular Expressions, there is no reason to stringify
					resources in code.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="References to Resources">
			<content>
				<p>
					Sometimes, resources may be stored in a hashmap, keyed by strings. However, accessing
					resources using string keys is more expensive than directly using object references,
					despite the computational complexity of <i>O(log n)</i>.
				</p>
				<p>
					Sometimes, string keys may be stored for later references using a hashmap. However,
					the memory usage and hashing computations could be significant when in hot calls.
				</p>
				<p>
					Therefore, when applicable, one should always opt to use object references when
					there is no special reason of using a string key.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="See also">
			<content>
				<list>
					<li><a href="../efp003">EFP 3</a></li>
				</list>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
