<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="" created="2026-03-21" category="standard" status="draft" title="Compact Staged Versioning">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="20"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					This versioning system is suitable for a major end product consisting several versioned systems.
					This refers to Semantic Versioning (SemVer) for basic reference.
					In certain scenarios, it may be difficult to version an end product when underlying components
					evolve in different extents and directions, so this basic methodology is introduced.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Basics">
			<content>
				<p>
					Version string format is as below:
				</p>
				<code-block lang="ABNF">
					version = &lt;stage&gt; "." &lt;major&gt; "." &lt;minor&gt;
					stage = "0" / "1"
					major = number
					minor = number
					number = *&lt;positive-digit&gt; &lt;digit&gt;
					positive-digit = %x31-39 ; 1-9
					digit = %x30-39 ; 0-9
				</code-block>
				<p>
					For <code>stage</code>, zero ("0") means Early Development and one ("1") means Mature State.
					For <code>major</code>, frequent incrementation would be expected with breaking changes often occurring.
					For <code>minor</code>, insignificant miscellaneous changes may instead increment this value,
					but not any breaking changes should be included while patches are often included here.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Extension">
			<content>
				<p>
					Implementers may extend this string format in any way meaningful for their purposes.
					This includes allowing pre-releases or snapshots, or branched releases.
					Extending this basic Rule by the pre-release version rules defined in SemVer is also compatible.
				</p>
				<p>
					Often, in Early Development, zero <code>major</code> may mean Alpha stage of development while
					non-zero values may imply Beta stage of development. In this case, when <code>major</code> is zero,
					<code>minor</code> may include breaking changes as this stage implies unstabilities.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="See also">
			<content>
				<list>
					<li><a href="https://semver.org/spec/v2.0.0.html">SemVer v2.0.0</a></li>
				</list>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
