<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="" created="2026-02-11" category="informational" status="draft" title="Programming Levels">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="13"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					This document introduces an advisory explanation of programming levels, widely categorized
					as "<i>low level</i>" and "<i>high level</i>" in different contexts.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="General Meaning">
			<content>
				<p>
					In general, low-level programming indicates that the specific piece of code with
					a certain level of raw manipulation of computer resources. Thus, extra caution is always
					necessary as this structure may contain unobvious but critical code that may lead to
					unintended behaviors.
				</p>
				<p>
					In this case, usually compiler warnings or errors, or even runtime errors, may not
					indicate the actual issues induced by a previous change, for the reason of extra caution.
					As a general advice, checking the compliance to intended behaviors by debugging the code,
					and checking the previous change may typically help.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Abstraction Levels">
			<content>
				<p>
					Sometimes, abstraction programming may also contain, so-called "<i>low-level</i>" code.
					In this sense, when a piece of abstract code contain a little amount of abstraction,
					it may be said to be <i>low-level</i>. In the codebase written in high abstraction code,
					low abstraction code may still be used somewhere, to act as a backbone of the higher-level
					counterparts.
				</p>
				<p>
					When low-level abstraction code is to be handled, it should be treated like generally
					low-level code. However, low-level code patterns should not be present in high-level
					code to maintain the level of code.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
