<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="6" created="2025-05-23" category="standard" status="draft" title="TerraModulus Game Logging Framework">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="10"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					Logging would become one of the core utilities of the <i>TerraModulus</i> game application, that all
					other parts would rely on. This proposal discusses all the practices and the structure of the logging
					framework for the game application.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Service Base">
			<content>
				<p>
					The surface utility would be provided by
					<a href="https://github.com/oshai/kotlin-logging"><i>kotlin-logging</i></a> with its underlying
					SLF4J 2 interface. The logging provider would be Log4j 2 with SLF4J bridge. However, all these
					interfaces should be hidden in the <code>common</code> module of the application, but exposing
					the configured custom public interface defined in the application for other modules or dependents
					for usage.
				</p>
				<p>
					There would only be two appenders for the logging framework. Both are formatted using simple
					patterns, but structural logging is yet not applied until it becomes essential to be fed into
					the Launcher for log ingestion. The log message should contain full timestamp in the local
					timestamp, thread ID, log level, full logger name and the message, represented as
					<code>%d{DEFAULT_NANOS} [%T] [%p] %c: %m%n</code>. There is no standard about how exceptions
					should be logged, so exception logging relies on the library's default behavior.
					Please note that logging to console should enable highlighting but disable to non-console
					standard output for the Launcher to ingest; this is controlled by
					the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) escape code option.
				</p>
				<p>
					The file logs should be handled in a way that old logs are compressed in LZMA2 with
					configuration tuned efficiently for text. Therefore, when all logs are logged in a directory
					of <code>logs</code> from the root of data directory, all existing logs with extensions of
					<code>.log</code> should be compressed before creating a new log file for the current session.
					This may be done by defining a custom plugin to be used for configuration. Please note that
					having more than one instance of the game application running over the same data directory
					is illegal, so only one instance should hold the new log file, and this should be initialized
					only when <b>instance duplication</b> checking is completed.
				</p>
				<p>
					All logs from all log levels should be outputted to both the file appender and the console
					appender. This allows the Launcher to act as a supervisor to ingest and filter logs to
					display to users from the standard output. However, verbosity should not be <b>too high</b> by
					default, to prevent unreadable logs to users. Logging should be done in a separate thread
					or asynchronously to reduce performance impact to other threads; this may be done by using
					<code>AsyncRoot</code>.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Logging Practice">
			<content>
				<p>
					Logging should always be enabled regardless of target, but certain elements may not trace
					or debug information when they are <b>too verbose</b>. That is, if they contain too much
					information for debugging, mixing other information at the same time, they may be used either:
				</p>
				<list type="decimal">
					<li>Only in development debugs, enabled by uncommenting in source code; or</li>
					<li>By inserting an argument option in launcher arguments for tracing specific parts.</li>
				</list>
				<p>
					When some logs are controlled by launcher arguments, inlined helper functions could be
					used to simplify the logging code.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="See also">
			<content>
				<list>
					<li><a href="../efp003">EFP 3</a></li>
					<li><a href="../efp004">EFP 4</a></li>
				</list>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
