<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
	efp="1" created="2025-01-26" category="process" status="provisional" title="Constitution of the Organizational Architecture">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="1"/>
			<pullRequest id="3"/>
			<pullRequest id="15"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Purpose and Scope">
			<section title="Establishment">
				<content>
					<p>
						This Constitution establishes the Organizational Architecture of the <b>TerraModulus</b> Project
						as the foundational framework governing the scope of the Project, including
						the administration of the Community, and the underlying executive parts for the creations,
						lifecycles and relationships of Execution Framework Proposals (EFPs),
						Executive Policy Charters (EPCs), Executive Research Dossiers (ERDs) and
						Community Standards and Guidelines (CSG).
					</p>
					<p>
						The Architecture consists of the Project, the Community and the Executives.
						All Members in the Community have their own rights and responsibility with respect
						to the Project.
					</p>
					<embed src="./constitution.svg"/>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Authority">
				<content>
					<p>
						This Constitution is the supreme authority within the Architecture.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Legitimacy">
				<content>
					<p>
						All EFPs, EPCs, ERDs and CSG derive legitimacy from this Constitution.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Scope and Jurisdiction">
				<content>
					<p>
						This Constitution is limited to the scope of the Architecture.
						All activities within the Architecture are still covered by the local jurisdictions.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="Governance Principles">
			<section title="EFPs">
				<content>
					<p>
						EFPs are community-driven, execution-defining, and immutable once finalized.
						They provide standards, methods, and structured execution plans.
						This includes but not limited to strategies, projects, guidelines and standards.
					</p>
					<p>
						EFPs shall either:
					</p>
					<list type="decimal">
						<li>
							outline how a project, procedure or initiative will be executed, managed, and monitored
							to achieve its objectives; or
						</li>
						<li>
							explain or define a certain mechanism which would be applied onto the Architecture.
						</li>
					</list>
					<p>
						Both the Community and the Executives may initiate an EFP to the Architecture.
						The EFP might also take effects over the entire Architecture besides
						the Community and the Executives.
					</p>
					<p>
						In general, EFPs do not require the mandatory approval from the Executives.
					</p>
					<p>
						An EFP may represent the stance of the Executives or the Project in any aspect.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="EPCs">
				<content>
					<p>
						EPCs are executive-led, versioned, and policy-defining.
						They establish organizational principles, governance structures, and policies,
						but must always be initiated and guided by corresponding EFPs.
						Both EPCs and their associated EFPs must be approved by the Executives before becoming authoritative.
					</p>
					<p>
						An EPC is a formal document with authoritative language that outlines the policies, principes,
						and governance structure for the Architecture.
						EPCs may serve as Rules and Regulations under the Architecture.
					</p>
					<p>
						Any EFP in the draft, shall associate an EPC if the EFP is purposed to initiate an EPC.
						However, the association requires the Executives' approval.
					</p>
					<p>
						All participants, including the Community and the Executives,
						are required to adhere to the EPCs whenever their designated administrative scope is applicable.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="ERDs">
				<content>
					<p>
						ERDs are structured summaries or compilations of research findings, insights,
						and recommendations to provide high-level overviews of research foundations
						and may inform EFPs and EPCs.
					</p>
					<p>
						ERDs may involve consulting, market researching, policy analysis or strategy investigations.
						They may also be comprehensive on a particular topic which may affect the Execution of the Architecture.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="CSG">
				<content>
					<p>
						CSG are derived directly from EPCs.
						They provide operational and administrative guidance for the Community.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Executive Systems">
				<content>
					<p>
						On the whole, over the Architecture, document systems such as EFPs, EPCs, ERDs and CSG,
						have the special roles and purposes by their own definitions.
					</p>
					<p>
						The details of processes, regulations and guidelines for each document system shall be
						defined clearly in their corresponding EPCs.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="System Inheritance">
				<content>
					<p>
						An EFP or EPC may directly inherit another EFP or EPC from another Governance System respectively,
						when both Systems share the same mandatory features.
						In the inheritance, terminology amendments aligning to the System shall be made in the same document.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="EFP Process">
			<section title="Purposes">
				<content>
					<p>
						EFPs are publicly visible and allow open project supervisions by the public, while keeping
						the project workflow streamlined enough. These could provide clear guidelines and information
						about various topics, so as the processes. This would also allow certain public involvement in
						the project while keeping certain intent of organized workflow.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Filing">
				<content>
					<p>
						The identifiers of EFPs shall be strictly sequential as the serial number starting at one.
						The identifier shall be assigned only when the initiation of the EFP is approved.
						After that, the document entry shall not be declined or removed regardless.
					</p>
					<p>
						The title of an EFP shall not be changed once finalized.
					</p>
					<p>
						Deprecation of an EFP must be caused by another EFP.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Content">
				<content>
					<p>
						An EFP may involve the Architecture, a mechanism, a plan or a scheme.
						It may not be highly executive, but may involve certain objectives, deliverables,
						or boundaries of the Project.
						There may not be time constrains, but the milestones and objectives may be decided in the roadmap.
						Moreover, it would be intended to standardize and guide the Project or a process.
						Occasionally, certain EFPs may solicit feedback from the Community depending on the context,
						so EFPs may be updated and revised upon feedbacks or progressions.
						However, the topics or the themes of the EFPs should not be changed,
						or else a new EFP should be issued for the new content and updates.
						Certainly, detailed descriptions should always be included to ensure that the goals and
						methods are generally understood, except for the progressional development of the thoughts
						to be included in the related ERDs.
					</p>
					<p>
						EFPs may contain both normative and non-normative content at the same time. It may be up to
						the decision of the author(s) for the final interpretation of the contents, including but not
						limited to the parts of whether the related contents are to be normative, non-normative or
						outdated.
					</p>
					<p>
						Once finalized, the EFPs shall become immutable, but maintenance and errata may be allowed.
						This includes minor content modifications without effects to the designated meanings and
						metadata changes of the documents.
					</p>
					<p>
						The formats and management details should go into the corresponding EPC.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Classification">
				<content>
					<p>
						EFPs are first classified into two types:
					</p>
					<list>
						<li>
							An <b>Informational</b> EFP is non-normative, and describes background, explanations
							or other information about various topics to the public, without formally proposing anything.
							It may also provide insights, overviews or advice about certain topics.
						</li>
						<li>
							A <b>Normative</b> EFP is formal, and describes or propose normative features, changes,
							mechanisms, processes, workflows, standards, protocols, specifications, or various principles.
							It may also provide guidelines, recommendations, best practices to the Architecture,
							or may include implementation change or interoperability standard for the Projects.
							It may also be a realization or implementation of a standard or specification.
						</li>
					</list>
					<p>
						And then five categories:
					</p>
					<list>
						<li>
							<b>Organization</b> EFPs describe the overall system of organization of the Architecture
							and relationships between different items or projects under the Architecture.
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>Project</b> EFPs describe executions special to a particular project or
							a specific range of projects for a given case.
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>Governance</b> EFPs describe miscellaneous governing tasks or policies,
							and management of governing systems like EFP, EPC and ERD.
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>Standard</b> EFPs describe descriptive standards, protocols and specifications.
						</li>
						<li>
							<b>General</b> EFPs describe uncategorized miscellaneous information about anything else.
						</li>
					</list>
					<p>
						EFP categories can be understood as the scopes where the EFPs are applicable to.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="EPC Process">
			<content>
				<p>
					A full EPC identifier includes a serial number and a revision version string.
					EPC streams shall be strictly sequential for the serial number,
					with the major version as the year of issue of an EPC version,
					and the minor version as the sequence of issue in an EPC stream in the year.
					An EPC stream is a collection of all versions of an EPC under the same serial number and title.
					Since EPCs are versioned, new versions of an EPC may override or supersede the older versions
					of the EPC series.
					However, a deprecation of an EPC may not lead to or be caused by another EPC.
				</p>
				<p>
					There is no specific categorization of EPCs, but EPCs may be informally grouped by their
					purposes and aspects of topics.
				</p>
				<p>
					When there is a change in the title, or a thematic change in the EPC,
					a new EPC stream must be initiated.
					A revision of an EPC means modifications in the content without major changes.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="ERD Process">
			<content>
				<p>
					ERDs are topic-based, and are sequential by stages or time in streams.
					A full ERD identifier includes two serial numbers.
					ERD streams shall be strictly sequential for the major serial number,
					with the minor serial number be the sequence of the document in the stream.
				</p>
				<p>
					ERDs as Topics may be extended from another Topic from another ERD,
					potentially with another related topic or as a subtopic of another one.
				</p>
				<p>
					Occasionally, ERDs could be the procedures of creating an EFP or an EPC, but with more
					explanations or progressive conversions, organized by chapters.
					Also, an ERD may be conducted when an EFP or an EPC is to be initiated, so it is not
					necessary for a corresponding EFP or EPC to be drafted after the related ERD.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="CSG Process">
			<content>
				<p>
					For EPCs to be declared to be entries of the CSG, the Executives must additionally approve
					the registrations of the EPCs to the CSG.
					Each CSG stream consists of a strictly sequential serial number, a title and a primary definition.
					Each CSG stream defines the purposes according to the primary definition.
					If any of the title or the primary definition has changes, a new stream shall be initiated.
					Any CSG stream may or may not be effective according to the status of the stream's purposes.
					Each CSG stream may be overridden or superseded by another stream, or solely deprecated.
				</p>
				<p>
					The title of the CSG entry may differ from that of the source EPC.
				</p>
				<p>
					CSG series may be informally made for different sets of CSG for the Community's convenience.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Formation of the Executives">
			<section title="Executive Leadership">
				<content>
					<p>
						The Executive Leadership holds authority over the Executives.
					</p>
					<p>
						The Executive Leadership shall be decided by the host organization of the Architecture
						without participation of the Community.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Chief Governance Officer">
				<content>
					<p>
						If available, a Chief Governance Officer may be assigned to cooperate with the Leadership
						in ensuring compliance with this Constitution.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Supreme Governing Group">
				<content>
					<p>
						The Executive Leadership and Chief Governance Officer together form the Supreme Governing Group.
						Amendments and explanations of this Constitution must be approved by the Supreme Governing Group.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Authority">
				<content>
					<p>
						The Executives holds authority over the Architecture.
						However, most executive operations over the Architecture require the formal process of an EFP
						to allow the oversight from the Community.
					</p>
					<p>
						Essentially, the organization holds the supreme authority over the Architecture while
						the Community shall hold the majority authority besides the Executives.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="Formation of the Community">
			<section title="Governing Moderator">
				<content>
					<p>
						If available, Governing Moderators may be selected from the Community to aid in
						the procedures of several document systems.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Rights of Supervision">
				<content>
					<p>
						Fundamentally, all Members of the Community have the rights to supervise the Executives
						through participation in administrative activities.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Participation">
				<content>
					<p>
						Community Members may engage in discussions and initiations of EFPs, EPCs, and ERDs.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
			<section title="Accountability">
				<content>
					<p>
						In cases of dereliction of duty by the Executives,
						the Community may challenge the Executives through corresponding procedures defined in EPCs.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="Amendment of this Constitution">
			<content>
				<p>
					Given that this Constitution per se is an EFP, it is bound to follow the processes inherent to its nature.
				</p>
				<p>
					This Constitution may only be amended by extraordinary consensus of the Supreme Governing Group.
				</p>
				<p>
					When there are some amendments on certain sections, various EFPs could be created to <i>update</i>
					the target version of this Constitution. However, if the amount of modifications is high such that
					a separate new EFP has to be created, the new document should be named under literally the same
					title with no additional decorative words.
				</p>
				<p>
					For any future administrative activities in the Architecture, the latest version of this Constitution
					should always be referred as this Constitution, so the necessity to mention the revision in the EFP
					document's title is negligible.
				</p>
				<p>
					It is possible that non-normative references to the latest version of this Constitution may be
					made for the public's reference. In this case, all amendments should be included in the references,
					and the actual EFPs of this Constitution remain authoritative over the references.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Archival and Transparency">
			<content>
				<p>
					All executive documents such as EPCs, EFPs, ERDs, and CSGs, must preserve historical versions
					for transparency.
					All amendments and archives must be publicly documented.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="See also">
			<content>
				<list>
					<li><a href="https://rust-lang.github.io/rfcs/0002-rfc-process.html">Rust RFC Process (RFC 2)</a></li>
					<li><a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0001">Python Enhancement Proposal (PEP) Purpose and Guidelines (PEP 1)</a></li>
					<li><a href="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2026">IETF's RFC 2026</a></li>
				</list>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
