<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="13" created="2026-03-24" category="standard" status="draft" title="Orryx Application Extensive Modules (AXMs)">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="23"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					"<i>Mod</i>", is commonly known to be an abbreviation of "Modification", but here, since there are
					not <i>actually core contents</i>, there is nothing can be said to be "Modification".
					Thus, informally, "Mods" may be referred to be Modules or Application Extensive Modules (AXMs),
					and "Modding" can be referred to be a system of AXM; AXM System is a general system for
					application extensive behaviors (AXBs), while AXBs may also be known as
					Downloadable Contents (DLCs) in commonly known terminology.
					Types of AXBs include Resource Packs, Mods, Integrated Gameplay Packages, Maps (Game Worlds), etc.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Default Contents">
			<content>
				<p>
					By the game itself, if no AXM is loaded, there should be no any gameplay contents.
					However, the Launcher may provide default AXMs to be installed for officially default gameplay
					contents as the basic contents, which may be in the sandbox survival genre.
					Other than this, Orryx is purely an engine without any gameplay contents built-in except for some
					essential supporting modules.
				</p>
				<p>
					There is no "default" contents as the concept, but built-in functionalities, algorithms and systems
					within the frameworks. For examples, there may be built-in algorithms provided by the Core for
					world generators.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Namespacing">
			<content>
				<p>
					All AXMs must have a namespace, with optionally subnamespaces. All resources provided by the AXMs
					must be under its namespace; while being referred, they may be under its AXM's namespace.
				</p>
				<p>
					Certain contents may be Core AXMs for officially supported AXMs, including Application Public
					Interfaces (APIs) and playable contents; however, additional official AXMs that are not Core but
					other Projects may also be available. Therefore, namespaces of "core", starting with "core-" or
					containing the words "terramodulus" or "terramod" shall be reserved and prohibited for public's uses.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
