<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<efp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../efp.xsd"
     efp="15" created="2026-03-27" category="standard" status="draft" title="Orryx Ferricia Physics Engine">
	<metadata>
		<pullRequests>
			<pullRequest id="25"/>
		</pullRequests>
	</metadata>
	<body>
		<section title="Introduction">
			<content>
				<p>
					Physics is the most basic feature for an open-world game to run. "Physics" here only refers to the
					interactions between and kinetics of physical objects in a World, without interference from other energy.
					In Orryx, physics may be parameterized for Application Extensive Modules (AXMs) to extend and
					customize physics behaviors for their own implementations of worlds. Most of the computations
					related to physics shall be run in Ferricia, with certain parameters and attributes configurable
					by the Kryon layer. Some of them may even be sometimes constant while variable the other times.
				</p>
				<p>
					While the entire physics engine is based on Open Dynamics Engine (ODE), most working details would
					likely be explained in terms of it. However, several conceptual ideas may also be explained in mechanical
					physics, likely with related theories, laws, algorithms and formulae.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Basic Concepts">
			<content>
				<p>
					Since TerraModulus is tile-based, or <i>block</i>-based, in most of the time, Tiles should be stationary
					and rigid with contact of other Tiles. However, Entities may act in any way, with various possible
					motions and combinations, even potentially with joints and islands.
				</p>
				<p>
					Units and coordinate system in physics engine should one-to-one align with the ones seen in Kryon.
					This means, the x-axis, y-axis, z-axis must comply exactly the same across those systems.
					For basic units, meters and Newtons may also be used, as they are the units used in ODE.
				</p>
				<p>
					There would likely be special measures for moving Tiles. Since Tiles are expected to be aligned with
					integral coordinates, moving instances that do not meet this criterion may be undefined.
					Therefore, moving Tiles shall likely be implemented as special Entities with some effects being Tiles,
					unless Tiles are instantly moved without any transition.
				</p>
				<p>
					Most likely all bodies shall have uniform mass, although implementations may still use ununiform
					masses in certain bodies for special games. Most bodies likely do not rotate except for certain
					bodies in certain Entities, so forces applied on should be uniform without causing torques.
				</p>
				<p>
					Certain geometry objects would be implemented with special meanings. World boundaries should be
					planes, while others may be created in any way for Tiles and Entities. However, Tiles as non-placeable
					may be as collision spaces containing several geometry objects including boxes. Some objects without
					certain shapes may be made as meshes, but this should not be common. There is no plan to include
					arbitrary Worlds, so heightfield and convex shall not be used. Other than these, no custom classes
					shall be implemented. It is a question whether Tiles should be implemented as composite bodies.
				</p>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section title="Implementations">
			<content>
				<p>
					Although, there is likely no default complete physics implementation, certain common configurations
					may still be possible to be made officially as simple implementations for ready-for-production
					developments of other contents without having to implement their own ones by their own.
				</p>
			</content>
			<section title="Simple Terra">
				<content>
					<p>
						As a simple interpretation of an open world with simple and common interactions in various games,
						this implementation may be simple, though certain parameters may still be made. This may resemble
						the physics as on Earth, but gravity may be configurable for authors with a default value.
					</p>
					<p>
						Most Tiles and Entities should be inelastic; world boundaries should also be completely inelastic.
						However, certain Tiles and Entities may be elastic, from configurations by authors.
						Without specific settings, those bodies should be inelastic, including collisions between Entities.
					</p>
					<p>
						There would likely be two modes for Tiles, where for one, all Tiles fall while the other only
						certain selections of Tiles may fall.
					</p>
					<p>
						Physics Engine shall be initiated via <code>PhyEnv</code> as the root handler when a World
						is being initiated along with other World resources. Then, other World, Space, Body and Geom
						instances are created as initialization of resources. A <code>PhyWorld</code> holding
						all physics objects belonging to it is created by<code>PhyEnv</code>. Most likely all physics
						objects should have respective handles, and the <code>PhyWorld</code> only hold references to them.
						<code>PhyObj</code> has two implementations, <code>PhyBody</code> and <code>PhyGeom</code>,
						where <code>PhyBody</code> is the physics representation of a Body or Geom. <code>PhyRawGeom</code>
						fully holds a Geom but translation to <code>PhyGeom</code> destroys it.
					</p>
					<p>
						In the structures with ODE, <code>PhyEnv</code> shall hold <code>OdeHandle</code> handling library
						utilities and <code>CollisionManager</code> for collision handling assistance.
						<code>PhyWorld</code> shall hold <code>OdeWorld</code>, <code>TopLevelSpace</code> and a list of
						<code>PhyObj</code>. <code>TopLevelSpace</code> is the top-most Space, holding <code>OdeSpace</code>.
						<code>OdeWorld</code> is used to handle <code>OdeBody</code> while <code>OdeSpace</code> is used
						to handle <code>OdeGeom</code>. <code>PhyBody</code> holds either or both an <code>OdeBody</code>,
						or one or more references of <code>OdePlaceableGeom</code>. Associations of ODE Geom and ODE Body
						are handled by the abstraction of them in <code>PhyBody</code>. ODE Bodies are always created in
						<code>OdeWorld</code> while ODE Geoms are always created in <code>TopLevelSpace</code>.
					</p>
					<p>
						User-defined data should not be stored in ODE objects, but only on our side with those handling
						the interactions with those ODE objects. Mostly, <code>phy::ode</code> module handles abstraction
						of actions provided by ODE's interface, while other higher level operations should reside in
						<code>phy</code> module directly. Seemingly, Kryon's internal would directly interact with
						objects in <code>phy</code>, and indirectly with objects in <code>phy::ode</code>.
					</p>
					<p>
						For flexibility to support other physics libraries, the abstraction layer in <code>phy</code>
						module should be generalized enough with certain supporting functions. This includes that
						library-dependent interfaces should not be exposed across the Java-Native Interface.
					</p>
					<p>
						<code>PhyEnv</code> shall also handle collision activities observed by executing ODE's loop.
						<code>CollisionHandler</code> from <code>PhyEnv</code> handles collisions by generating
						<code>OdeContactJoint</code> from <code>OdeContactGeom</code>, while all parameters depend on
						properties of objects in interaction. Those properties should be defined by properties of
						Tiles and Entities, so they are fully up and subject to Kryon.
					</p>
				</content>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section title="See also">
			<content>
				<list>
					<li><a href="https://ode.org/wiki/index.php">Open Dynamics Engine (ODE) Community Wiki</a></li>
				</list>
			</content>
		</section>
	</body>
</efp>
